<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: github | Dirty Geeky Things]]></title>
  <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/blog/categories/github/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-20T17:14:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kallsey.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Natasha Callender]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OMFG aka How I ended up using Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/omfg-aka-how-i-ended-up-using-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-19T17:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/omfg-aka-how-i-ended-up-using-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How hard does easy have to be? The post, which never ended up posting, below explains my search for a dead simple blogging system. Well… One that did not involve me putting up a static site and uploading html files all by my lonesome.</p>

<p>I thought I had found the perfect solution in one of the Dropbox/Markdown blogging engines. They sounded perfect. I should have known better. Neither Calepin or Scriptogram played nicely with my custom domain. They each had their positive points, but I want to be able to use my domain, not myname.yourcleverbrandna.me.</p>

<p>Ask the person that married me, I enjoy playing with tech. I will gleefully spend hours making hard things work, but I do not want my blog to be a hard thing. I want it to be easy. Why? Because I can be lazy, and if I’m feeling lazy and updating this blog is hard, this blog will not be updated.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> which I rejected yesterday, because setting it up required more steps than I had patience for, but (and this is a very big but) Octopress worked. It was more complicated than I wanted. It took longer to setup than I wanted, but it worked on the first try.</p>

<hr />

<h4>Keep It Simple Stupid: The original blog post on dead simple static blogging</h4>

<hr />

<p>Remember the iPhone 4 vs HTC Evo video? <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FL7yD-0pqZg">Here’s</a> a refresher if you don’t. I was the “I don’t care” guy today regarding publishing this blog.</p>

<h4>Wizardly Templates: I don’t care</h4>

<p>I do not, for this blog, give two bucky wukkups about how fancy it looks. I just want it published and looking semi decent.</p>

<h4>Out of this world content management: I don’t care</h4>

<p>My personal tech blog will consist of just words, maybe a picture if I’m not feeling super lazy. As such, I don’t need content management. I just need a way to get my content online</p>

<h4>Super simple Ruby/Python/Whatever setup using Liquid/Moustache/Whatever templating system: I don’t care.</h4>

<p>Hacking is fun. As this blog will attest, I love learning new things but for the love of Christ… I just want to a dead simple way to publish git versioned static files to in the internet with zero fuss.</p>

<h4>The solution <em>for now</em></h4>

<p>The solution, for now, consists of fun with Markdown-Dropbox blogging platforms. This <a href="http://www.fearofconfusion.com/2012/01/three-markdown-dropbox-bloggging.html">site</a> has a good run down of the options.</p>

<h5>The Trials</h5>

<ol>
<li>I tried and abandoned <a href="http://scriptogr.am/">Scriptgr.am</a> it looked pretty but the lack of an obvious way to use a custom domain was a deal breaker.</li>
<li><a href="http://skrivr.com/">Skrivr’s</a> website is divine. Call me shallow, but a website that pretty just begs for the product therein to be used. Alas, it is invite only. I will try it as soon as my invite comes in.</li>
<li><a href="http://calepin.co/">Calepin’s</a> setup was a breeze, and the information I needed on custom domains was on the front page. Guess who won?</li>
</ol>


<h5>Likes/Dislikes and things about which I am indifferent</h5>

<ol>
<li>I like the Dropbox/Markdown combination. It has the potential to fit almost seamlessly into my Scrivener/Dropbox/Markdown workflow which will be discussed in a future post.</li>
<li>I like that my files sit in a simple directory in my Dropbox folder. Versioning will be simple.</li>
<li>I <strong>love</strong> that updating my blog is as portable as anything else using my Dropbox account.</li>
<li>I do not like that I have to go to their website and publish the posts through a dashboard. I am a command line kinda girl. I want the option to not have to log in to a website to publish.</li>
<li>I am indifferent about the looks. It isn&rsquo;t the prettiest site in the world, but it loads fast and is functional. Usability expert Jakob Nielsen used to maintain one of the ugliest but oh so very useable sites on the interwebz. It has been taken down, but the original can still be seen <a href="http://chnm.gmu.edu/digitalhistory/links/cached/chapter4/4_2_useit.htm">here</a>.</li>
</ol>


<p>More to later when that Skrivr invite comes in.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
