<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogging | Natasha Callender]]></title>
  <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-21T18:50:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kallsey.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Natasha Callender]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[natasha.callender@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[working-with-markbox]]></title>
    <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/working-with-markbox/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-21T18:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/working-with-markbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Of the dropbox/markdown solutions, <a href="http://www.markbox.io/">Markbox.io</a> and <a href="http://skrivr.com/">Skrivr&rsquo;s</a> seem to be the ones with the most promise. This does leave me to wonder why dropbox/markdown baked blogs are not really catching on. It seems like an obvious solution, and come on, all the techie types likely to use this sort of thing have dropbox accounts and probably worship at the altar of markdown. Is this blogging method too new, or is it that there&rsquo;s something here people do not trust? Time will tell, nevertheless I like the idea of it and I am going to try.</p>

<p>Both markbox and skrivr require invites to their paid accounts. I don&rsquo;t like the idea of adding another monthly bill, but ehh&hellip; $6 US isn&rsquo;t that much of a hardship. I already pay $3 just to not have to listen to ads Pandora. Word to the developer &ndash; I love, love, love that my monthly commitment to Pandora shows up as a subscription on my Google Play account. Something to think about when everything is up running and working as you would like it.</p>

<p>My markbox.io invite came in a month ago. The initial setup was a breeze, but I ran into two roadblocks. The first was that naming of the blog did not work out quite like I expected. The default blog address is/was username.new.markbox.io. According to the instructions I should have been able to log in, setup my account and rename the blog to username.markbox.io.</p>

<p>No joy!</p>

<p>It turns out that the developer(s) have moved the service from Google Apps to another provider. I suspect that the kinks in pointing blogs created with the new system to the naming convention of those created with the old have not been worked out yet. This is a little annoying, but I can live with it.</p>

<p>The second roadblock was, as usual, my using a custom domain name. It is possible, but requires a $10.00 one time fee and the hosting of the name on by markbox&rsquo;s service. <strong>That is not going to happen.</strong> The fee is small enough that I do not care, but I am not moving my domain name.
The DNS entries setup just the way I like them, www. and blog. point to my baked blog hosted on Github pages, mail. and cal. point to my google apps account. It works, and has been working for several years &ndash; the Google Apps part at least. I do not want to touch it.
The ideal would be to be able to point the CNAME records for www. and blog. to username.markbox.io in the same way that they currently point to username.github.com.</p>

<p>This brings me to what I like about markbox.io &ndash; besides it being a really good idea in theory. Based on my earlier frustrations, I put the service away and out of my mind, but earlier today after receiving an email reminder that the trial period was nearing its end, I decided to give it another look. An <em>this custom domain issue thing is a dealbreaker</em> email garnered what has been an encouraging email exchange with the developer, Steve Ivy.
The jury is still out on whether or not the custom domain issue will work the way I need it to work, but the fact that Steve is willing to have a conversation about it bodes well for the future of this product.
He was also very upfront about what features are not ready,  namely static pages and custom tags. I can live with those limitations for the time being. I&rsquo;m not sure how I feel about paying for less than what I already get for free, but sometimes you just have to suck it up and support a service you believe in. This maybe one of those cases.</p>

<p>My conversation with Steve inspired the writing of this post with the intention of putting it up on my markbox blog. There were, of course, some stumbling blocks. These revolved around the process for making a new post not being clear. By this I mean, what are the rules for making a post:</p>

<ol>
<li>Is there a naming convention for the title?</li>
<li>Is there meta data that needs to be included at the top of the post</li>
<li>How are new posts recognized</li>
</ol>


<p>To the best of my knowledge the answers to these questions are as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Yes</li>
<li>Yes</li>
<li>Go to the <strong>posts</strong> section of the dashboard and hit <strong>update</strong></li>
</ol>


<p>The first two answers were obvious <strong>to me</strong> because I already use a baked blog, and those are the rules of baked blogging. However, but it would not be obvious to someone who is not familiar with baked blogging. This sort of problem is solved with clear instructions, and possibly a post generator.</p>

<p>It would be nice, if updating the blog was as simple as opening my favorite text editor, writing something, and saving, but the tech does not seem to be there yet &ndash; at least markbox is not there yet. Based on what I saw from the homegrown markdown/dropbox solutions available on <a href="https://github.com/myfreeweb/markbox">Github</a> getting there is not easy.
Will we eventually have a dropbox/markdown blogging solution that regularly scans a your-dropbox-account/Apps/blogging-app/posts for new entries, automagically adds the appropriate meta data to the new entry, and re-saves it with the correct filename? If there is a large enough user base asking for it, then yes? Does it already exist? I do not know. I have tried everything but <a href="http://skrivr.com/">Skrivr&rsquo;s</a> and none of them had such functionality it. Maybe <a href="http://skrivr.com/">Skrivr&rsquo;s</a> does &ndash; I will not know until they get around to sending out another round of invites.</p>

<p>Where does this leave me, and what sometimes feel like my Sisyphean quest to find a dead simple blogging solution? Using my Octopress blog until Steve comes back with an answer on the custom domain question. If the answer is yes, I can do it the way I want, then I (and my custom Octopress template) will happily move over to markbox blogging. If not, then the quest will continue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Close But No Cigar]]></title>
    <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/07/21/close-but-no-cigar/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-21T14:16:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/07/21/close-but-no-cigar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Octopress is not the solution for me. Let me be clear, it works. The setup went fairly well. There were a few hiccups, but nothing that could not be solved with a few minutes of Googling. It is smooth, fast and, as these things go, painless <strong>BUT</strong> it does not fit in with my preferred workflow.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I like writing markdown blog posts in Scrivener, and then exporting the .md files to a location of my choice. I am experimenting with using Scrivener external sync feature to auto update a Dropbox/Markdown blog, that is if I can ever find one that works the way I want it to. In a perfect world I would be able to prepare the post in Scrivener, export it to my Dropbox, and have my blog updated automatically. Simple, clean, easy.</p>

<p>My Octopress workflow is a little more involved.</p>

<ol>
<li>Use  rake new_post[“title”] to created new post with correctly formatted <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/frontmatter/">YAML Front Matter</a></li>
<li>Prepare the post in Scrivener</li>
<li>Open the document from step 1 in Mou or Sublime Text 2</li>
<li>Cut and paste the post from step 2 into the .markdown document</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>The Clunk Burns My Eyes</strong></p>

<p>I could spare myself a few steps and simply compose the entire blog post in Mou or Sublime Text 2, but that would mean throwing my carefully constructed Scrivener work flow out of the window. You will see in future posts why I am reluctant to do that.</p>

<p>Finally, it is just not portable. These days I leave my laptop home most of the time, and just take my Android phone or tablet with me. Being able to blog/work from any of my devices is a deal breaker. Now I could be clever and install Octopress on my shared hosting account, and ssh into the server and do what I have to do that way. There are several fine ssh clients available for Android devices, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.connectbot&amp;amp;hl=en">Connectbot</a> being my favourite. There are also a few good markdown compatible text editors available for Android as well. I bought <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mvilla.draft&amp;amp;hl=en">Draft</a> a little while ago and could not be happier with it.</p>

<p>I could also setup an always on Linux box in my basement, install Octopress on that and ssh into that from anywhere when I want to make a blog post. I could do these things, and I would get a kick out of making it work too. However, I just want to write my blog, not show off my technical skills.</p>

<p>This may sound odd, but I find that getting older has dampened my zeal for doing clever, geeky things just because I can. These days I am more likely to find and use the simplest solution that works. Keep It Simple Stupid has become my philosophy of technology. My goal in every situation is to find the simplest solution that does exactly what I need it to do, when and how I need to do it.</p>

<blockquote><p>“Perfection is Achieved Not When There Is Nothing More to Add, But When There Is Nothing Left to Take Away”</p></blockquote>

<p><em>&ndash; Antoine de Saint-Exupéry</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OMFG aka How I ended up using Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/omfg-aka-how-i-ended-up-using-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-19T17:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kallsey.github.io/blog/2013/07/19/omfg-aka-how-i-ended-up-using-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How hard does easy have to be? The post below (which never ended up posting) explains my search for a dead simple blogging system. Well… One that did not involve me putting up a static site and uploading html files all by my lonesome. <!--more--></p>

<p>I thought I had found the perfect solution in one of the Dropbox/Markdown blogging engines. They sounded perfect. I should have known better. Neither Calepin or Scriptogram played nicely with my custom domain. They each had their positive points, but I want to be able to use my domain, not myname.yourcleverbrandna.me.</p>

<p>Ask the person that married me, I enjoy playing with tech. I will gleefully spend hours making hard things work, but I do not want my blog to be a hard thing. I want it be something I can make it to a system. Why? Because human beings respond well to systems.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> which I rejected yesterday, because setting it up required more steps than I had patience for, but Octopress worked. It was more complicated than I wanted. It took longer to setup than I wanted, but it worked on the first try.</p>

<hr />

<h4>Keep It Simple Stupid: The original blog post on dead simple static blogging</h4>

<p>Remember the iPhone 4 vs HTC Evo video? <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FL7yD-0pqZg">Here’s</a> a refresher if you don’t. I was the “I don’t care” guy today regarding publishing this blog.</p>

<h4>Wizardly Templates: I don’t care</h4>

<p>I do not, for this blog, give two bucky wukkups about how fancy it looks. I just want it published and looking semi decent.</p>

<h4>Out of this world content management: I don’t care</h4>

<p>My personal tech blog will consist of just words, maybe a picture sometimes. As such, I don’t need content management. I just need a way to get my content online</p>

<h4>Super simple Ruby/Python/Whatever setup: I don’t care.</h4>

<p>Hacking is fun. As this blog will attest, I love learning new things but for the love of Christ… I just want to a dead simple way to publish git versioned static files to in the internet with zero fuss.</p>

<h4>The solution <em>for now</em></h4>

<p>The solution, for now, consists of fun with Markdown-Dropbox blogging platforms. This <a href="http://www.fearofconfusion.com/2012/01/three-markdown-dropbox-bloggging.html">site</a> has a good run down of the options.</p>

<h5>The Trials</h5>

<ol>
<li>I tried and abandoned <a href="http://scriptogr.am/">Scriptgr.am</a> it looked pretty but the lack of an obvious way to use a custom domain was a deal breaker.</li>
<li><a href="http://skrivr.com/">Skrivr’s</a> website is divine. Call me shallow, but a website that pretty just begs for the product therein to be used. Alas, it is invite only. I will try it as soon as my invite comes in.</li>
<li><a href="http://calepin.co/">Calepin’s</a> setup was a breeze, and the information I needed on custom domains was on the front page. Guess who won?</li>
</ol>


<h5>Likes/Dislikes and things about which I am indifferent</h5>

<ol>
<li>I like the Dropbox/Markdown combination. It has the potential to fit almost seamlessly into my Scrivener/Dropbox/Markdown workflow which will be discussed in a future post.</li>
<li>I like that my files sit in a simple directory in my Dropbox folder. Versioning will be simple.</li>
<li>I <strong>love</strong> that updating my blog is as portable as anything else using my Dropbox account.</li>
<li>I do not like that I have to go to their website and publish the posts through a dashboard. I am a command line kinda girl. I want the option to not have to log in to a website to publish.</li>
<li>I am indifferent about the looks. It isn&rsquo;t the prettiest site in the world, but it loads fast and is functional. Usability expert Jakob Nielsen used to maintain one of the ugliest but oh so very useable sites on the interwebz. It has been taken down, but the original can still be seen <a href="http://chnm.gmu.edu/digitalhistory/links/cached/chapter4/4_2_useit.htm">here</a>.</li>
</ol>


<p>More later when that Skrivr invite comes in.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
